when it starts to happen, there's an AI
theme behind it. I want to make sure
people realize when it comes to crypto,
this is 100% for me about agents. And
I'm telling you, the amount of
traditional people that continue to bang
on my door to talk about tokenization,
to talk about how to make money on this.
They're doing their homework now. I
think next year is going to be the year
that we see the biggest moves in crypto
because of it. What's going on, guys?
Today, we got a great conversation with
Jordy Visser. In this conversation, we
talk about what's going on with AI
agents, how crypto and Wall Street are
coming together. Then we talk about the
idea of this going from a contrarian to
a consensus trade. And then Jordy and I,
we debate a little bit as to general
purpose models versus specialized
workflows. Where is value going to acrue
in the AI industry? And then we get into
the bubble talk. All these people
worried about a big bubble. And Jordy
helps us separate both the signal from
the noise. Here's my latest conversation
with Jordy Visser. All right, Jordy.
This week there's a Bloomberg piece
about you. The Bloomberg piece said,
"Forget the AI bubble." Jordie Vesser
says, "The bank apocalypse has begun."
Congratulations on the uh Bloomberg
coverage. You're a big deal now. Um but
>> they waited for me to say something
negative.
>> Negative. They didn't say anything
positive.
>> No, no, no. The media loves a bearish
thing.
>> Well, bank apocalypse will definitely
get clicks. Uh what is the bank
apocalypse and why do you think it is
coming?
>> So, I posted an X that morning. I didn't
see the article until someone pointed it
out to me. Uh we've talked about it
before, but I really did a lot of it on
my my video last weekend. So rather than
turn this into some like the banks are
all going to go to zero thing, the
software companies went through their
SAS apocalypse. So number one thing,
it's a play on the SAS apocalypse thing.
SAS got hurt for two reasons or two two
stories behind it. One is the
recognition from people that AI was
going to disrupt seatbased SAS software.
Not all of software. Cyber's done well.
Bitcoin miners have done well. They're
in there as well. Microsoft's been fine.
But the reality was AI hurt these
companies despite the fact that they
continue to print for the most part
record earnings.
And that was a sign if you remember in
that first quarter, one of the most
important signals for everyone to think
about when it comes to sectors is that
because of exponential innovation and AI
continuing to increase progress, at some
point it will be a negative for almost
every single industry and especially
legacy industries. And I just want to
make sure because I tried to I tried to
show that in the expost and I'll use
some of that here. I believe the banks
now are going to go through a problem
which is they're going to come under
multiple compression over the course of
the next year because of two factors.
One is the rise of AI agents which means
consumers are going from let's say lazy
individual small businesses have their
money in banks that pay them zero yield.
That's really good for the banks when
the banks can take your deposits of
which there's a lot pay you zero
take that money invested in treasuries
yielding 4% short-term not like SVB did
long-term but shortterm uh you can get a
spread on this so we saw the article
from Torston Sllock with an agentic bank
run so he was going a different angle
but that's part of it and I don't want
to say that there's going to be a run
because that's what's going to happen.
What I want to say is that agents are
not going to make mistakes. They are
going to search for the cheapest way to
do thing and that means that as agents
control more of the money decisions,
banks are going to be in trouble. The
second thing is that the guardrails are
going to apply pressure as well. And
this is where crypto fits in. So when
you have the users, the consumers no
longer being humans but being digital
agents and at the same time you have
financial guardrails which are being in
the system more where there's same day
settlement which means stable coins
which means tokenization. We're headed
towards that settlement. Long-term
settlement is a good thing for banks,
for Visa, for Mastercard. The longer it
takes for some, somebody gets that
float, somebody gets the chance to
invest that money for a day, for 3 days,
and if an instant settlement, it's not
the same. So, this was really a a belief
that banks will still make money. Um,
but the spread, the edge that they had,
their multiples over the future are
going to be hit by terminal value again.
So, it's not a like doom and gloom
thing. I kind of played with the SAS
apocalypse to create bank apocalypse.
But that is what in in my opinion is
certainly going to happen with the rise
of consumer agents.
>> Is there a positive to this? Like the
consumer wins in this scenario?
>> Yeah, the consumer wins. The people who
um invest in the financial guardrails
are going to see more traffic. So if you
invest in crypto and it's a small asset
class, you'll do well. The the only
place I see getting hurt is the
middlemen. And so labor verse capital
has been an issue. The consumers, we
have a K-shaped economy. Anything that
is going to make it more powerful to
bring, you know, inflation down, at
least on the service side, uh, is going
to be positive in the long run. So your
question, everyone should be thinking
about it. What's the positive side?
Well, the positive side is if we can
reduce the fees, you'd be shocked at how
much money the banks take purely on a
spread basis from everyone. Well, the
reason I say that is uh we never see the
headlines of the positive news. Like uh
one of the chapters in the book I just
wrote actually I don't know if you know
this is uh uh planes that land safely
never make the news right and so like
same thing here is when people see
disruption occurring they always cover
it from the angle of who is being
disrupted. They never are like consumers
will make X billion dollars more because
they now will have their money not
parked in you know low yielding assets
or whatever. So, the perspective I think
matters, but it also plays into I don't
know if you saw Paul Graham uh this
week, uh Amazon made the decision to
stop I think it was Muse and some other
bots or agents from accessing Amazon.
And he came out and I thought it was
probably one of the most interesting
perspectives uh this week was the first
time in decades that he believes someone
could expose or exploit a wedge to
disrupt Amazon. and his point was if
somebody could build an Amazon that was
made for the agents
>> that could be very disruptive. Now,
Shopify, I think, is leaning into, hey,
how do your agents come and buy things
and do all this, but that feels like the
banks are the same thing. Like, if
somebody builds a bank that is
agentfriendly, it's probably going to be
pretty valuable, right? Well, let's
separate the bank, meaning where you
place your money. If they pay you the
fair spread, meaning if you deposit
money in a bank and they pay you and all
you're doing is I'm getting interest on
that money, then there's the other
service side. They call you up. We want
you to invest. You know, they all own
brokerage houses. They all own they want
they want to make sure they're making
money. This is this is the service side
of the business. Stripe is not a bank,
but Stripe is competing with all of
them. And that's what I included in the
piece. This weekend I will go through
about 15 slides of Stripe. City Bank is
a $200 billion market cap company with
$200,000 people.
Stripe has 10,000 people. It's about $
160 billion currently off the latest
valuations. If you go through their M&A
activity, if you go through their
volumes, their revenue is up 41%
year-over-year according to them. You go
through every metric in their revenue
side. They have already built for the
crypto world. They already are set up
for this. They're already set up for the
agentic side. They've been talking about
agentic commerce for a long time. These
older banks, of which I worked for one,
it's very hard to get through the
bureaucracy and make a decision. They've
always had the ability and this is one
of the things that I think people should
just really listen to when it comes to
something that I feel by using AI and
why I try to help people use it as much
as you can. The progress is insanely
fast. As you and I both know, these
businesses never move fast into
something. First of all, there's a
calendar year, the summertime, nothing
gets done. And then you come back in
September and they start focusing on
when they're going to pay people for
bonuses. And that process, trust me,
it's a while. Then they've got to do 360
uh reviews. Then they have to hand out
the bonuses. They have to sit and put a
budget in for the next year. This is all
time. AI doesn't wait for that. Stripe
doesn't wait for that. They don't have
the amount of people that Croup does.
They don't have to bring in the managers
from overseas. They don't it's a it's a
completely different side. So I think
the nimble companies and what Paul said
about Amazon, if I remember exactly what
it said, he basically said never in
their history have they been in have had
to do this. The reason I think this is
important for people to think about when
it comes to the hyperscalers, I say all
the time, you have to look at how these
Mag not the Mag 7, but let's well let's
say the Mag 7 became so big. They don't
compete with each other for the most
part. Apple, Apple has its own business
model. Amazon has its own business
model. Google has its own. AI agents cut
through all of them. They all want
consumer agents. And if they start
playing this game of we're not allowing
Muse to come in because we're waiting on
Alexa. And then Siri does the same
thing. Apple also announced they're
changing the iOS and they said it was
because they didn't want agents
penetrating. So, they use the scare
tactic as opposed to no, we don't want
agents to get into this. I would love it
right now if my AI agent in Muse could
get my Apple messages. It would make
make it a lot easier. I think they're
all now in trouble that they're all
basically trying to defend their turf.
So, they're playing for the same TAM
now. And that means that their business
to me is being disrupted. And I think
Amazon, what Paul Graham wrote is just a
sign that they don't know what to do
because these companies are big
bureaucracies. Now,
>> uh Elon Musk tweeted uh two or three
days ago saying that Grock was going to
open up the backend to any model. And
for those that are unfamiliar, um, if
you use OpenAI, they will give you
either a model that you select or if you
are just talking to ChatgBT, they may
route your query to an OpenAI family of
models. They would never send your query
on ChatgBT to Anthropic, Claude, etc.
Grock historically has used their
internal stuff, but now they're opening
it up and they're saying, "Well, we're
going to actually just route to whoever
is the best model." To answer your
question,
if that forces the hand of the other
players, to me, that signals that the
models are commoditized and now the
value of those models becomes much more
in question than they already are. I
personally think that's where we're
headed. like we bet Sylvia on this of
building a model router and saying hey
we don't really care what the model is
we just want it to be the best one to
answer uh for the uh end user now Elon's
doing it does that force open AI and
anthropic both to open up themselves as
well or do you think that they can keep
these kind of closed you know kingdoms
and uh similar to how Amazon seems to be
kind of creating a closed kingdom like
we we're playing this game of like
bundling and unbundling that is like the
story of you know business and finance
for decades
So, this is the one place where you fit
in with the masses. So, when we when we
talk like I disagree with where you're
headed with this,
>> okay,
>> um, and I I've heard this repeatedly
from people over the course of the next
six months. This is not exactly what
you're saying, but it's pretty close.
>> Open AAI and so ChatGpt and Claude are
the best models, plain and simple. Like,
I don't care what anyone says to me as
someone who uses all of them and has
used open source models. The best model
right now is Opus 5.5. The next best
>> for general general purpose stuff.
>> No, no. For the stuff that I do, so that
includes images, video, like a general
model that will do everything that I
need. Not like Gemini makes a lot of
mistakes and it comes back with answers
that are ridiculous. Opus 4 Opus 5.5 is
a game changer. Now, here's the thing.
>> You tell Gemini it's silly.
>> You know, it's the most disrespectful
thing you can say to a man. It's just
you're silly.
I don't understand.
So I I'm maybe it's because I use them
so much that
>> I don't get frustrated by the answers. I
don't have to explain twice to them. And
trust me, you have employees and you
know which ones you might have to say
something twice to.
>> Listen, I today's episode is brought to
you by Arch Public. Arch Public has just
expanded its agentic trading platform
beyond crypto. So pay attention. This is
a big one. Now, they are automating
strategies across stocks, commodities,
and ETFs. And I think that this is going
to be huge. You can now automatically
take profits when one market hits new
all-time highs and rotate that capital
into other markets, showing more
opportunity. Whether you're rotating
capital into AI stocks, gold, if you're
investing in the S&P 500, or you're
accumulating Bitcoin, Arch Public brings
real discipline and automation to your
investment strategy. Additionally,
they've launched a powerful new tax loss
harvesting tool. With crypto being so
volatile and its exemption from the wash
sale rule, Arch Public can offset gains
with losses without compromising your
long-term positions. It's exactly what
every serious investor does.
Institutional grade automation that
works across every major asset class.
There's no more emotional trading, no
more missing tax opportunities, just
smarter, hands-free execution of your
preferred strategies. Go to
archpubic.com
right now. Connect with their team. Set
up a time. Bring your accountant if
you'd like. Then you can learn what
automated trading can do for you.
archpub.com.
>> I'm a very big believer and uh have
always said I think that people
underestimate the importance of their
intuition because it is you know it's
your human algorithm. You've been
training it. Just as there are
benchmarks that are these like objective
open- source benchmarks that all the
models try to you know game or whatever
you have a Jordy benchmark and what
you're describing is that opus is 5.5 is
the leading model in the Jordy
benchmark. Yes. And it's not just for
me.
How many times does Grock get announced
as solving the greatest math problems
ever? How many who's in the fight for
that? Like it's not just me. Who finds
an enzyme for crisper?
Okay, that used to be Google. That's
what Alph Go was. That's what Alpha Fold
was. That's not what's happening
anymore. The stuff that's happening is
in these models. And here's the issue.
when you start realizing how much
compute is needed for consumer agents.
So the Paul Graham thing what what you
didn't see Elon
also posted that and said seriously like
this is we're going to have
commoditization in intelligence. There's
no doubt about it. The difference is and
what people don't realize the amount of
compute you have leads to the models
being more efficient. So, if you haven't
felt this yet,
I'm I'm surprised the cost of the models
for like Opus 5.5, they're getting more
efficient because they have a ton of
compute power behind it. But if it takes
you
2 minutes to get to an answer in Opus
5.5 and a cheaper open-source model
takes you 12 minutes. When you add up
the token usage and the cost and it
comes through, the time does matter. not
just the answer. And I think everything
in AI is about the time relationship to
the probability of getting the right
answer. So everyone only talks about the
cost side. That's not the way the world
works. We have cheap cars. We have
expensive cars. Like everything in life
becomes that. I just think for solving
cancer, for solving the greatest
problems in the world that people are
going to need to get to space to do
this, we're getting there's going to be
highlevel things that are going to take
these models. And the problem is
Anthropic and OpenAI are going to own
most of the compute going forward. And
if the compute matters that much, which
it will because I still will keep saying
and I hear this on the other side,
people still fight on like there's a
bubble coming like we are so early in
the demand side of tokens. So early the
coding agents didn't even exist a year
ago. So that just started the adoption
that means for corporations we went
through token maxing. Now we're going
through okay we can't throw this much
money at it. We have to be more
efficient with our thoughts. Well,
they're figuring out how to do that. The
models keep progressing and getting
better. And Ver Rubin's going to come
out next year. As Ver Rubin comes for
the same amount of gigawatts, you're
getting more. Well, who owns most of
that? The really smart groups own most
of that. So, that's where OpenAI
Anthropic, but also Elon Musk, he owns a
lot of it, too. He's been buying as much
Ver Rubin as he can. So, I think we're
going to get to a point as you move down
the road that the open source is fine
for the majority of tasks. 90% of them
will be close to zero. But for the 10%
the total TAM of that 10% is going to
continue to grow through adoption. And
that's where Jevans paradox actually
matters because the cost of it and the
efficiency will keep going. And that's
really important for people when they
think about investing because I will
continue to say there are two themes
that I care about right now. Agentic
compute. So the AI infrastructure and
the financial guardrails. That's what I
believe over the next one year will
create the alpha. And if you look back
over the last four years, the alpha has
all been about AI.
>> So I have uh somewhat of a hot take.
>> Good.
>> The big labs already are behind in two
very important ways. What are the
leading personal agents?
Muse and Instinct, not the big labs. I
know they launched DOTs. We'll see what
happens, but Muse and Instinct are out
in front leading in those two.
When you look at specific applications,
legal, finance, etc., the large language
models are not the leading models.
They're leading in general purpose, but
when you start to get specific, they're
not. When you look at it on a cost
perspective, I can just go off of our
data. If I process 500 million tokens
from uh on Claude, about $5,000. If we
process the same 500 million tokens on
our own model and our own hardware, it's
97% cheaper. So
what I think is going to happen, but I
think the fact that you and I don't
agree on this actually is like maybe
that's the story of like nobody really
knows, right? Is you're going to start
to see the large language model say we
got to pick our battles. Where do we go
and fight to win because just having the
general purpose model is actually not
going to be as valuable because of the
commoditization. And so we should
accelerate into specific use cases.
Anthropic recently announced that
they're going to go really heavy into
bio and all the biotech stuff they want
to go do. It feels like they think that
is a massive opportunity. If they can
win there, that is trillions of dollars
of value that they can create. Open AAI
is saying dots and personal assistant.
They've always been more of a consumer
type company than an enterprise type
company. And so I don't think it's just
like, hey, go all in on one specific use
case, but it does feel like they're now
realizing that the general purpose model
can serve as like a foundation, but the
monetization of this and the sustainable
moat is going to be in the applications.
And this goes back to the idea of in
crypto, if you go back to 2017 or so,
there used to be this thing called the
fat protocol thesis. And the whole idea
was like all the value acrrues to the
protocol layer. And I could be wrong on
this, but I just continue to go back to
the fat protocol thesis. The equivalent
in the AI is like the fat model lab
thesis where all the value acrews to the
model lab.
What we found in crypto was there is
definitely some value that acrrews to
the protocol obviously bitcoin,
ethereum, etc. But actually a ton of the
value acrewed to either the
infrastructure underlaying it in terms
of miners and things like that or the
application layer. It feels like that's
the same thing happening here where as
the technology gets built out, we have
tons of infrastructure that's making
money, we have tons of applications that
are yet to be built, but I just find it
really hard if like Anthropic and Open
State as general purpose model
providers. I just think that is like a
cutthroat business. It's like kind of a
race to zero. Who can get the, you know,
highest level intelligence for the
cheapest cost? And so like what's the
moat? What is the the the, you know,
thing that defends against everybody
else? But I don't know, maybe you think
differently.
>> I do. Um
I don't think the application So when
you say Muse and these things, how h I I
I don't understand how Muse is going to
make money.
>> Oh, I think they're going to print cash.
>> Okay. So, I don't understand how they're
going to
>> because again, the they have a couple of
decisions they need to make, but let's
use Instinct as Amuse's uh uh kind of
proxy. What they very clearly are trying
to do is they want to get as much
transaction volume going through that
personal agent as they can and they
think they can basically take a vig and
my guess is that they will go and start
pressuring whether it is the credit card
companies, the payment processors, the
merchants etc. and say, "Hey, I'll route
stuff your way, but you got to give me
something." Right?
>> So, M or uh Instinct is going after a
transaction-based revenue model. He has
said that he would like to keep it free
forever.
>> Facebook, they got one business model.
>> Yeah.
>> And you and their target is about to get
way better, right? And so, whether it is
actually transactions where they get
paid or the advertising is where they
get paid, I worked inside that business.
Trust me, if you're going to use their
products and you're going to give them
more data, they're going to get better
at ads. And so to me, it's not Muse
makes money as much as Facebook makes
money. They just happen to own the Muse
thing. And look at like WhatsApp like
that. They've started to do this across
a lot of their interfaces. Um, and I go
back to when I opened up Instagram and
I've got a interstitial at the top of my
Instagram feed that's like download
Muse. They're going to get people to
download it. They're going to get the
data. then they're going to target you.
>> Did you listen to the Noah Shinar
interview?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. When you say ads, that's he called
that the attention economy.
>> The attention economy is going to
collapse.
>> Maybe
>> I I I personally I I don't I mean part
of what's going to happen, it is very
clumsy at this point to have to use your
phone for your personal agent.
>> Agreed.
>> Okay. So that's why they're all trying
to figure out the next gadget to go
through. By by the way, uh I think that
Instinct, which we really haven't heard
Meta talk as much about this, but
Instinct, he specifically uh he wants to
monetize the transactions and what he
his belief, which I actually agree with
him on, is the agents transacting should
lead to more transactions, which
therefore it's like a market expanding
technology for both the merchant, him,
everyone kind of wins in that because
the consumer also gets served.
I think in the attention to come you're
talking about like yeah if the agents
are perusing or looking for something
serving a display ad in the feed of
whatever is not going to be very
valuable and so I is there going to be
like agentto agent advertising here
here's the point and this is where we
can end this conversation um I only
believe there's two things to focus your
attention on the toll collectors
>> that's crypto
>> as far as I'm concern. I want the
digital money guardrails, the toll
collectors.
>> I don't want I don't want to invest in
Muse and then watch as seven other
agents are released and that's before we
have agents in Europe and agents in
Asia. Like this is the thing. We have
competition globally.
>> I just want to collection velocity. I
don't want the attention economy. These
are all things to me of the last 17
years. I want to bet on the things that
we are always going to have demand
greater than supply.
>> Mhm.
>> We will not have enough compute for the
agents. That is the way to play what
you're describing. In my opinion, the
competition, it's all going to be
commoditization. The reason I say I
don't agree on the anthropic and open AI
is because I think there's infinite
amounts of money for super intelligence
and they're going to have it. Open
source models can never have the size
intelligence they can because they can't
have the compute. All of these places
they don't have the compute. So they can
keep copying distilling the models but
at some point you need this because we
won't release the best models to the
market. They will go to the businesses
>> and that's where it can't be
commoditized. So at some point people
have to realize if you have the compute
you get the best model. If you have the
best model and it can solve all the math
problems, then every single science and
physical place humanoids will want that
model. You don't release it to the
public. And if you don't release it to
the public, how do you distill all the
information if it's not a public model?
>> Maybe this is like the root of where we
see a different world. I don't think
that uh Claude will be able to create a
model that outperforms a company. Let's
say that you're a huge law firm. Let's
say you're a huge finance firm.
>> If you take open source models and you
customize them via fine-tuning to your
specific architecture, your specific
data, etc., you should be able to out
compete them.
So again, how many business are going to
do that? Do they have the talent? It
cost money. Like there's a lot of
whatifs in there. But if that is the
case, I guess that's where I get a
little bit more less enthusiastic is
just like you can keep iterating on the
model, but it's still a general purpose
model. Yep.
>> The businesses that say, "Hey, we're
going to build custom models for
ourselves."
>> You can show up with the smartest model
you want, but they're like, "But it's
not customized to us." And so the
business is less likely to go do it.
Now,
>> I think to your point, that's a black
and white analysis. What's probably
going to happen is the business like
give us all of it and then we'll figure
out what we use and over time they'll
kind of fall away but they'll try almost
everything. And that's kind of what we
saw. There's a Wall Street Journal
article uh that says uh the title is
spending on AI is becoming almost
impossible for businesses to budget
which is basically this story, right?
>> And it's it's a great one. So I I we'll
leave it at this. I I don't disagree at
all with what you're saying. The models
will not be the models behind a law
firm. Those will be more open source and
cheaper things. The problem is the law
firm will end up being a oneperson law
firm and a billion of them. So if you're
like I hear you talking and and I think
you think differently than I do in the
endgame, which is I don't want to be a
VC fund. Like I don't think you can pick
the winners in the world you're
describing because I believe it will
always be an entrepreneur that says I'm
willing to make less
>> 100%.
>> And I'm going to build a business and I
don't I only need to make a hundred
grand a year. So when people ask me how
to like and this was asked to me
yesterday's like okay I'm I'm I'm in my
20s. I want to I want to be a part of
this. I'm watching your videos like okay
focus on signal verse noise. Don't
listen and just keep working hard. AI is
going to keep going. The alpha as you're
stacking your chips building a poker
chip which you're getting through your
job. If you don't feel like you're
growing fast enough in your job, then go
build an app on your own and collect
10,000 and then go build a second app,
collect 10,000. Believe it or not,
because of Stripe, you can do that.
Like, you can create an app that
competes with the world. And if you
create 10 of them, they're each
making$10,000 and that's $100,000 and at
your job you're making $115,000. Then
you can quit your job and go create
these regularly and build up a stack and
invest that money and it compounds. I
met people at your event. That's what
they basically do. They've made their
financial wealth through investing by
not listening to the bubble talk.
>> Mhm.
>> We got to do some bubble talk. It was a
bubble week again.
>> Well, why?
>> I want to talk Bitcoin and bubble. I've
had enough of of tech.
>> What's going What's going on with
Bitcoin?
>> I think I beat him into submission
there.
Did you just cry uncle?
>> May maybe maybe this is us. It's like us
at Thanksgiving now. We we were together
twice this week. Maybe it's it's
>> for those that don't know, Jordan and I
try not to talk during the week, so we
can come in here, but we we had a
midweek uh midweek session and so, you
know, we're we're uh we're
>> it's like Thanksgiving at the Pompiano
House right now. I've been a guest for
two.
>> All right. What What is uh what's going
on with Bitcoin?
>> Uh it's consolidating. No, no, no. So, I
I I do want to give because I've a bunch
of people have asked and I I want to
make sure everyone hears this.
>> For Christ's sake, be patient,
>> Jordy. Why isn't it at 100K? Yeah,
exactly. Um, come on. It's October. What
happened?
>> Let me go through. I want everyone to go
bring up a chart of Micron. You know, we
talked about Micron when it was $100. We
talked about when it was 150. If you go
look at 2024,
we started this thing. A lot of people
in your office bought bought Micron.
Should I stay in it at 200? Should I get
out at 200? It went to 1,400. Now, if
you go back and look, it broke above the
200 day moving average, just like
Bitcoin, just like Ethereum, and then it
retraced back to it. It tested it. I am
not sure that's going to happen with
Bitcoin and Ethereum and the rest of the
crowd. But you have to go look at why
that happened. When it starts to happen,
there's an AI theme behind it. I want to
make sure people realize when it comes
to crypto, this is 100% for me about
agents. And I'm telling you, the amount
of traditional people that continue to
bang on my door to talk about
tokenization, to talk about how to make
money on this, they're doing their
homework now. I think next year is going
to be the year that we see the biggest
moves in crypto because of agents. And
so I just want people to realize that
I've watched this now a lot, but in
particular with the semiconductors. It
took a long time when it was obvious to
me because of AI, because we were going
to need an enormous amount of memory,
but very smart people were not on it.
And right now, there are a lot of smart
people running around saying we're in a
bubble. That prevents people from
jumping into anything. They see the
rates going higher. Everyone should be
grateful that with rates going up as
much as they are, somehow another crypto
went higher. with gold going down as
much as it has gone down, crypto somehow
has been distancing itself and going
higher. So, when you go through this
whole thing, I I I really do believe
people have to be patient with this. Um,
it's a bull market and I feel
comfortable in saying that because I
said when it was a bare market, we're
above the 200 day moving average, the
200 day moving average is pointed
upward. Just be patient. These things
can never go as fast as you want and the
thing that will accelerate it the most
is when the traditional finance crowd
comes into it. And for that, we need the
tokenization volumes to go higher. We
need the tokenization asset size to go
higher. We need the stable coin volumes
to go higher. That's why I talk so much
about Stripe cuz Stripe is talking about
this daily. It's happening. Every person
listening to this show, you probably own
Bitcoin and you got it the same way. You
paid full price on an exchange. But
there's a smaller group of business
owners, family offices, and investors
with sharp CPAs. And they're quietly
getting theirs a very different way.
They own the machines that make it
mining. Here's how it works. You buy the
miners and Simple Mining hosts and runs
them at their facilities in Iowa on
industrial power rates that you can
never get on your own. The Bitcoin they
mine goes straight from your machine to
your wallet. There's two reasons I find
this interesting right now. One, the
economics. Cheap power let you convert
electricity into Bitcoin at a discount
to spot. You're acquiring the asset
below the sticker price that everyone
else pays. But second, and listen
closely, if you've got a big income
year, miners are classified as computer
equipment. Equipment means depreciation.
Qualifying buyers can write off the
entire purchase in year 1. It's the same
playbook real estate investors have run
for decades pointed at Bitcoin. Your CPA
will want to see this before the end of
the year. And so with attractive
financing available, you can deploy
these assets without selling any of your
assets to do it. This is not some garage
operation. Simple Mining runs over
40,000 machines and was just ranked the
fastest growing company in Iowa on the
Inc. 5000. They put together a valuable
resource called the 2026 Bitcoin Mining
Blueprint. It covers the five mistakes
investors make when allocating to mining
and how to avoid them before deploying
capital. You can access it for free at
simplemining.io/p.
That's simplemining.io/p.
Go check it out today. Today's episode
is brought to you by Abra, the secure
way to grow crypto wealth. Abra offers
individuals and institutions end-to-end
crypto wealth management solution,
including custody, trading, yield, and
cryptobacked loans through a unique,
separately managed account structure,
where title is retained by you, the
client. In other words, your assets stay
your assets. Abra's been partnering with
crypto holders for 8 years and has
processed over $2.5 billion in loans to
date. With Abber's loan product, you can
access up to 50% of the current value of
your collateral. There's no minimum or
maximum loan sizes and Abberra can
handle 9 figure plus loans. Rates are
extremely competitive in the 4.5 to 6.5%
APY range. Loans are open term, meaning
you can keep borrowing against your
collateral without closing a loan as the
price appreciates. Buy a house, take a
trip, make a large purchase, or
diversify your investments without
selling your Bitcoin. All deposits are
held in secure MPC wallets, and there is
no rehypocation. Find out more at
abra.com and tell them Pomp sent you.
Again, that's abra.com and tell them Big
Pomp sent you. So, in the last two
weeks, I have seen uh Black Rockck. I
have seen Bloomberg and also uh Citrini.
They put out a research piece with a
nice uh image that had DeFi on Wall
Street on it. And uh if I did not know
Catrini wrote it and I read through the
the notes of this, it could have been a
Jordy Visser piece in terms of the the
main message of there's this
intersection of crypto and Wall Street.
I think that some people will read some
of these other pieces, whether it's
Black Rockck, whatever, and be like, "Oh
my god, Jordy Viser's ideas are
infiltrating whatever." You said
something to me interesting though,
which is this is good because it means
that like we're transitioning from
almost like a contrarian view to
consensus view and you kind of need
that. Can you explain a little bit as to
as people see this idea show up in other
places why that's actually a positive
sign
>> it when you when you talk so the way
people view you
uh
>> oh
you've been positive on Bitcoin for how
many decades now?
>> Well Satoshi got the idea for me didn't
he here?
>> So I don't bring that up as as as as a
dig. I bring that up as once you kind of
have this story that you say over and
over again, and this works for me too,
your voice doesn't appeal to people who
don't believe in you because they go,
"Ah, he's a perma bull on crypto, so it
doesn't matter." So, in fairness, the
reason I'm saying this is if Jordy gets
viewed as someone who will only be
positive on Bitcoin, which isn't true.
>> No, you were bearish last year.
>> No, but bearish was
saying I I I was never bearish. What I
said is we're in a bare market like
acknowledging the facts. You can't fight
the market. Like the market is the
market. I believe the market knows
everything.
>> What we're trying to do is forecast what
the market will think in the future. And
people have to realize the only way you
make money in anything that you invest
in is not because you were right. It's
because other people that didn't agree
with you at the time came in and pushed
that asset higher. At the end of the
day, you are trying to bet where the
money is going to go, not where the
asset is going to go. So that is the
problem that happens. We I mean
Salesforce.com is down yet their
earnings are good. So fundamentals don't
matter. What's driving it? It's because
people were overweight SAS because they
had a view that it was a stable business
because private credit has a lot of
software. There's a bunch of reasons. So
for me, we need Catrini. We need
BlackRock. We need other voices to speak
up. In fact, I'm going to say this right
now. Jordy wants to go to as many
conferences next year. That makes sense.
Now, I'm saying this, you're going to
help me. I've already reached out to
Natalie. Like, I'm gonna I'm gonna get
out there because I do want to sit and
make sure that people hear why I'm
positive on it.
>> Jordy Vistler World Tour.
>> Yeah. I The one thing I don't
>> T-shirts made.
>> The one thing I don't hear enough about
is the connection that Catrini did,
which is agents to crypto is really
important. And it gets back to the Mark
Andre piece. And that's why I don't want
this to be about the basement. I don't
want, oh, the bonds are going down. The
government's going to have to step in. I
believe a year from now, it is very
likely that 10-year yields will be about
the same level a year from now as they
are today.
>> The only way I'll say they'll be lower
is because if the jobs market gets
noticeably weaker, which I don't think
it will over the next year, I definitely
think it's going to hover around zero.
But if it got weaker then the debasement
thing will become a bigger thing. But
other than that, it's because we're
growing so fast. What that me means is
the only thing that's driving growth is
AI. It's the only thing.
>> And so the bet becomes about AI. And I
have full belief that demand is greater
than supply over the course of the next
few years. So the buildout is going to
happen. The spending is going to happen,
which means nominal GDP is going to
happen. I don't think the government can
move rates down lower. And so if we're
going to run this thing hot, that means
the agentic world will continue to
accelerate and that means crypto is
going to do well. So I think the pieces
by Catrini, by Black Rockck, by everyone
is very important. I think where my edge
is in this whole thing is really
spending the time every single day of
connecting consumer agents importance to
what's happening right now. And when you
look at that chart that I've said so
many times from page 71 of situational
awareness, everyone should just
recognize that the chaos is going to be
worse next year than it is this year.
What we saw this year, all of the chaos,
the daily, oh, we're in a bubble, we're
this, it's only going to get worse
because people are overwhelmed with the
speed of change and we're going to
accelerate next year in speed of change.
>> How do they prepare and navigate that?
I it
signal verse noise is really important.
Um but how do you do it?
>> Okay, so this week a very famous hedge
fund manager Ray Dalio
was quoted as saying
bond yields may and I and I emphasize
the word may prick the AI bubble.
So this gets a lot of attention. People
send it to me and they go, "What do you
think?"
>> Bubble talk.
>> Now, if if this was said by, you know,
Joe Joe Smith on the corner,
>> by me.
>> Yeah. If Joe Smith got interviewed by
Bloomberg and said, "I think it may
prick the AI bubble, it wouldn't even
Nobody would care." But because Ray
Dalio said it, they care. But here's the
thing, and I'll show this this weekend.
Ray Ray Dalio. If you just go into any
LLM and say, "How often has Ray Dalio
said there's a bubble over the last 15
years?" It's a lot. And it's not to say
that he's not a smart guy. What it is to
say is he has now made a career, his
like post hedge fund career. He's
writing books about the history of the
world. He's a very smart guy in
understanding the history of the world.
So, he's saying we're going to end up in
the exact same thing that we've had. And
maybe we will. maybe they'll maybe
something will go on, but I think he has
a um a thesis that he has to stick by
and this is he's just going to keep
doing it. And so before it was a bubble
on something else and as I sent you
something and I'm going to show this
weekend,
if there was truly a bubble,
I think if we had a pandemic, the whole
market would collapse. Oh, check. We
already had that. It didn't do that. We
were back at new all-time highs and up
for the year. Okay. Well, if the Fed did
the fastest rate hike in the history of
the United States in an un unexpected
manner, we would certainly blow up this
bubble of 40 trillion in debt and the
whole world would collapse. We had that
one. Didn't do it. Inflation hit almost
10%. Didn't do it. Okay. Maybe after
they were done though, we'd see the the
after effects and we'd have the biggest,
fastest bank run in the history of the
country. Oh, check. We had that with
Silicon Valley Bank plus all the little
banks that fell too. We had deposits
flowing out. And guess what? New
all-time highs.
Maybe if we decided to go back to Smoot
Holly and we announced massive tariffs
around the globe, that would do it.
Okay, we fell 20%. Then we rallied back
to new all-time highs. Finally, this one
there's no way you can stop because
those were all kind of easy ones for the
Fed to print money out of. So, you could
think that they were going to print
money. What about if we shut down the
straight of Hormuse?
Every oil would go to 200, 300, 400, 500
and we would well we had that this year
can't print money and yet somehow or
another the market found a way to go
higher. So now the new one is rates are
going to do it. So I think people have
to just understand the way markets work.
We've had new all-time highs many, many
times during my career and there's been
many, many bad things that have
happened. And there may be another 20,
30% correction next year. And it might
be because rates get to such a high
level that we end up with, I don't know,
a bunch of businesses that we didn't
know had a lot of debt in Europe, in
wherever, that end up collapsing. I
don't know. But I also know that if that
happens, the governments have
financialized everything. So they will
come in just like they did after Silicon
Valley Bank and make sure that they put
money into the system to make it not go
down. A pandemic took trillions and they
did that. I don't know what other people
want to do. So I think when you listen
to these bubble talks particularly when
it comes to AI the way to navigate watch
my video. I am showing facts about the
demand verse supply. I am going to show
why Ray Dalio's conversation although
may be true
it's just the headline that he's put out
there the alpha which names are working
I'm literally going to go through and
say okay almost nothing has worked
nothing over the course of the last
decade very few companies have made
money if you go back to chat GBT only
24% of the companies in the S&P 500 1500
so 1500 companies only 25% % have
produced a return greater than the index
as a whole 25%. So it's very
concentrated. Guess what? We've been
concentrated for a long time with the
MAG 7. If you're trying to make money,
you need to know the things that are
working. The only thing that I think you
can make money on with the highest
probability of certainty
is things related to building out the
compute because we don't have enough of
it and we're going to continue to build
it out. On the other side, I think you
need crypto. So the alpha I'm trying to
give. And then finally, the best way to
feel empowered is to learn how to use
AI. If that's what's causing the
problems and that's where the biggest
fear is, if you want to make sure that
you know more than Ray Dalio, trust me,
he doesn't sit on an LLM all day. So go
build something, upload it to GitHub,
you have something over Ray Dalio that
he doesn't know about today's world. So
the agency side, the empowering side is
very important, too.
>> I could not agree more. What are you
going to do your video on this week?
>> I just kind of did it. It's a bunch of
that stuff. Uh we we just talked about
it, but in more detail and seriously I
uh I enjoy doing this. I had a great
time with the group that I saw and I'm
not kidding for people that in the
crypto community that are having big
conferences where you have a lot of
people where you think I can add some
value. I'm going to go to a lot of them
next year and before my calendar fills
up with things for you and for other
people that have first dibs, I would
like to be in a position where I can go
to places and talk. I think the most
important time to get back to your thing
about Catrini, Black Rockck, Joseph
Chalum, William Magguire, whoever you
listen to right now, the voices are
getting louder and louder on crypto. I
think making sure that people have a
chance to hear this and understand it
and learn from it is really important.
So, I think the next 12 months is is
something I regret with the Micron thing
of not really explaining to people, but
I didn't have a big enough audience.
Now, I have a big enough audience. So, I
want to make sure that as many people as
possible hear our show, but they also
learn about the importance of crypto.
>> The Jordy Visser World Tour begins
January 1st, 2027.
Book them now before his availability is
out. By the way, did you know that I'll
never ask you to go anywhere other than
in New York City? Cuz I don't go
anywhere for any event. Like, if we do
an event, it has to be in New York City
because I don't want to travel. Um,
>> I wish I had a video for everyone to see
that you and I passed each other in DC
where you didn't tell me you were going
to be there and it was literally not a
joke. You were going out of turn style.
I was coming in a turn style.
>> High fived.
>> Yeah.
>> And by the way, he was going and Jordy
Jordi is a amateur when it comes to
conference attendance. He was there for
like two days. All I went down on the
train in the morning, did my 15-minute
talk and went right back. I had the best
time I've had at an event with those
people in DC.
>> They were they were great. I I uh had to
come back for other reasons. But I have
one last thing, a surprise for you. Uh
did I hear that you read some of the
chapters of my new book?
>> Yes, I did.
>> The book is so good that I made Jordy
read. Just think about that. That's the
only ad you need. It
>> it got Jordy Visser to read a book.
>> It it it's it's really not a book. It's
a it's it's it's very similar to a book
that I love, The Daily Stoic, because
it's just passages. So, I can read like
a page I can read a page a week. I'll
finish it by the end of the year.
>> They're they're letters, so they're like
two pages long. Uh and there's 50 of
them. But I just I figured out what's
the best ad that I could make. Just the
book's so good, Jordy Visser read it.
>> And I love reading about spinach, so
it's fine.
>> The devil doesn't tempt you with
spinach. All right. Thank you all for
watching. We'll see you guys next week.